# **ISAAC A. HOLSTON**

108 Morrell Street • Colorado Springs, CO 80930 • (703) 657-9544 • isaac.holston@outlook.com

### Summary

Cybersecurity analyst with a **Secret Security Clearance** and 2 years of proven experience in the Missile Defense Agency. Possesses a comprehensive background in **Computer Programming, Information Security, Information Systems, Database Management, and System Configurations** derived from protecting and defending Department of Defense (DoD) networks. Seeking a challenging cybersecurity or software engineer position contributing to national defense and security.

#### Education

## B.S. in Computer Science, Graduated May 2018

Liberty University – Lynchburg, VA Cumulative GPA – 3.21

# <u>Skills</u>

- Software Development: Golang, Python, C++, Java, JavaScript, PowerShell, Bash, SQL
- Additional Experience: Docker, Git, LaTeX, MATLAB, NumPy, TensorFlow
- Operating Systems: Windows, Mac OS, Linux
- Professional: Team-Oriented, Strong Communicator, Critical Thinker, Problem-Solver

## **Experience**

#### MISSILE DEFENSE AGENCY (MDA) - Schriever AFB, CO

#### Cybersecurity Analyst

Sep 2019 - Present

- Led a team of security engineers focused on protecting MDA enterprise systems through network security initiatives to include issuing Cyber Tasking Orders (CTO), ensuring Security Technical Implementation Guide (STIG) compliance, reporting network compliance to Tier 1, and working with tools such as Host Based Security System (HBSS), Assured Compliance Assessment Solution (ACAS), and Network Security Manager (NSM)
- Performed detailed analysis of network traffic through packet capture, session recreation, traffic flow analysis, trending and open-source research
- Performed Independent Verification and Validation (IV&V) of Information Assurance (IA) controls under the Risk Management Framework (RMF) utilizing Enterprise Mission Assurance Support Service (eMASS) and controls validation testing through manual inspection, scanning, and interview
- Participated in penetration testing and security audits for several of MDA's operational systems
- Briefed high-level government, military, and contractor leadership teams regarding enterprise cybersecurity postures and provided cybersecurity recommendations and risk analysis

### MISSILE DEFENSE AGENCY (MDA) - Schriever AFB, CO

### Information Technology Specialist

Aug 2018 - Sep 2019

- Oversaw the implementation of security controls and their presentation to Authorizing Officials (AOs)
- Assigned as Information System Security Officer (ISSO); served as direct alternate to Information Systems Security Manager (ISSM) and assumed security manager duties in their absence
- Assessed and reviewed website unblock requests, software requests, source code cyber assessments, STIG
  risk acceptance requests, software plan of action and milestones (POA&Ms) and waivers for MDA
  Enterprise Networks
- Conducted risk and vulnerability assessments of planned and installed information systems to identify vulnerabilities, risks and protection needs for MDA Enterprise Networks
- Participated in network and systems design to ensure implementation of appropriate systems security policies

#### DOD SMART SCHOLARSHIP INTERNSHIP PROGRAM - Schriever AFB, CO

#### Scholarship Student at MDA

Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

- Provided program management oversight for missile defense capabilities and programs
- Worked with MDA Cybersecurity Emergency Response Team (CERT) to provide network security
- Participated in penetration testing and security audits for several of MDA's operational systems
- Briefed senior level officials on cybersecurity analyses and exercise test results

## Relevant Conferences & Activities

### COMPUTER SCIENCE CAPSTONE PROJECT - Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA 2018

- Developed web application written in Go programming language
- Collected and analyzed information on under-resourced people in the local Lynchburg area and connected them with relevant charity groups and services

## DEFCON HACKING CONFERENCE - Las Vegas, NV

2017

- Attended world's largest and longest running hacking and cybersecurity conference
- Collaborated with academia, industry, and government experts on state-of-the-art cyber tools

### NATIONAL CYBER LEAGUE (NCL) - Lynchburg, VA

2017

- Participated in individual NCL cybersecurity competition
- Developed skills in the following domains: Open Source Intelligence, Scanning, Enumeration and Exploitation, Password Cracking, Traffic Analysis, Log Analysis, Wireless Security, Cryptography, and Web Application Security

# **Certifications/Training**

- CompTIA Security+
- Defense Acquisition Workforce Improvement Act (DAWIA), Information Technology, Level I